GULBALA SALAMOV

+905367102202 | g.salamov@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub



PROFILE

I am a professional working in IT and enjoy conducting researches. Concrete and proven examples of my abilities include my involvement in successful projects, published applications, books, and articles. I am a positive thinker with strong communication skills and I thrive in team collaborations. I always aim to follow best practices for my own growth while contributing to others around me.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Turkish Airlines, Turkey Java Full Stack Developer

01.2023 - 06.2024

- Working on the design, development and integration of Java and Spring backend, as well as JSF and PrimeFace for frontend applications
- Reviewing and maintaining applications to meet new requirements throughout the software life cycle
- Providing workshops and technical supports to external customers regarding the usage of products
- Communicating between technical departments to identify and resolve urgent issues that critically impact business outcomes.

İBÜTEM, Türkiye 02.2022 –

LowCode/NoCode Developer & Technical Writer

- Building applications in OutSystems (LowCode Dev Environment)
- Creating high quality documentations, revising existing content

University College London, U.K. Android Developer & Researcher

04.2019 - 04.2021

- Maintaining data collection app using Java and Android SDK
- Designing new UI interfaces
- Contributing to academic research and workshops

State University of New York, U.S.A Technical Writer & Researcher (Intern)

06.2017 - 03.2019

- Writing technical content for Android programming text book
- Building interactive prototypes for university's mobile app

SIP, Azerbaijan 09.2015 - 09.2016

Web Developer & Business Analyst

- Building websites using WordPress, creating and managing content
- · Communicating with clients, verifying their needs and proposing solutions
- Simplifying complex technical concepts with high quality prototypes, use cases and diagrams to get feedback and improve the products

Middle East Technical University Foundation Schools, Turkey 09.2013 - 09.2014 ICT Teacher (Intern)

- Teaching students to build algorithms by playing logic based games
- Building simple apps using visual coding tools

EDUCATION

Swansea University, Birleşik Krallık

2014 - 2016

MSc, Computer Science

Middle East Technical University, Turkey

2010 - 2014

BSc, Computer Education & Instructional Technology

SKILLSET

• Programming Language : Java, Android,

Databases
SQL, OracleSQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL
Backend
Spring, Spring Boot, Oracle WebLogic Server

• Frontend : PrimeFace, JSF, CSS, HTML

• Tools : Git, Bitbucket, Jira, Confluence, Graylog

• Testing : JUnit 5

LANGUAGES

Azerbaijan — Native

English — Advanced

Turkish — Native

· Russian — Good

PROJECTS

#1 - Turkish Airlines Developer Portal

Description: A platform designed to facilitate the use of APIs provided by Turkish Airlines. The portal serves a gateway to their APIs allowing developers to enhance their applications with features related to flights, availability, promotion, airport information and so on. Link to source: https://developer.apim.turkishairlines.com.

Source : https://developer.apim.turkishairlines.com

Role: As a Java Developer, my role centered around designing and developing APIs for external parties, specifically promotional code usage and fare search. Here are the key highlights:

- Utilizing OpenAPI specifications, I configured our Promotion, Domestic Fare System (DFS), and International Fare System (IFS) API products within Apicurio Studio web based application.
- These APIs were then deployed Docker-like environment, ensuring scability and reliability.

Impact and Result: By implementing the RedHat 3Scale API Management product, I achieved significant results:

- Security: Robust authentication and authorization protocols helped the business to cut revenue loss by preventing attackers using web services to create promotion code and coupons. Several Information Security Vulnerability Records closed as well.
- Analytics: Leveraging API management tools, the team gained visual user and service analytics.
- Documentation Efficiency: The automatic generation of API documentation directly from the design, ensured accuracy, and improved communication with API consumers.

#2 - ECSAnVis

Description: Extreme Citizen Science Analysis and Visualisation (ECSAnVis) is a five-year, €2.5M project funded by the European Research Council (ERC). The project aims to develop geographical analysis and visualisation tools for non-literate communities and design culturally appropriate and aligned with specific needs of social practices of the target audiences.

https://www.ucl.ac.uk/geography/research/research-centres/extreme-citizen-science-excites/projects/extreme-citizen-science-analysis

Role: As a Java/Android developer, my work involved mobile application development, usability enhancements, and active participation in academic studies.

- I maintained the data collection app called Sapeli, fixed bugs and introduced new features to enhance user experience.
- Following HCI practices, I designed and implemented interactive prototypes using digital tools and contributed to building Sapelli Visualiser app to show geographically meaningful collected data.

Impact and Results: My contributions helped society and improved the usability of tools:

- Community Engagement: The apps enabled local communities to actively participate in scientific data collection and increased scientific literacy among participants.
- Stable App Version: Bug free, tested and more stable version of data collection app released.

#3 - Android Mobil Application Development Book

Android Sanatı (The Art of Android) is a book written to introduce the Android platform, providing entry-level to advanced structural content and examples, and to shed light on future software developers who want to develop mobile applications. It was recommended as an additional resource in Turkish universities in 2017.

https://www.kitapyurdu.com/kitap/android-sanati/434078.html